# 早上起来熬一锅棒子碴粥
After getting up in the morning, boil a pot of corn congee
# 把咸菜往火烧里一夹 这就是生活
And put some salted vegetables into a Huo Shao -- this is the life
# 特别家常的酱香咸菜丝
Home-made Soy Sauce Salted Turnip Julienne
# 香么 香
Can you smell aroma? Yes
# 咸菜疙瘩就这个
This a salted turnip
# 然后咱们就把咸菜疙瘩切成丝就行
Then we just need to cut it into juliennes
# 我是我师父收的第一个女徒弟
I am the first female apprentice of my master
# 所以在这行业里边
So in the cooking industry
# 他们都管我叫大师姐
They all call me “Da Shi Jie”
# 你看干活多快啊 麻利
Look, she is so proficient and deft
# 瞧这刀工 听这声儿
Look at the knife skill, and listen
# 关键步骤 得冲水
Here comes the critical step, washing
# 得多冲几遍 换水
You have to wash several times and change the water
# 没有咸味了 就是一点咸味不能有了
Make sure it’s not salty anymore, not even a little bit
# 我每次做这道菜的时候
Every time I cook this dish
# 我给我徒弟也讲
I always tell my apprentices
# 这是你们师爷 我师父教我的
My master once taught me that
# 有味使其出 无味使其入
“clear food’s original flavor if it has; add new flavor if it doesn’t”
# 这你师父从来没露过这句话
I’ve never heard this from your master
# 把咸菜的咸味给它洗出去
Get rid of the saltiness from the salted turnip
# 有的咸菜还犯点酸和臭味
Some salted turnip even tastes a bit sour and fetid
# 它那个发酵的快 它必须得弄出去
Salted turnip ferments fast, so we must clear its bad taste
# 你准备料吧 这儿我给你看着
You could prepare the seasoning now, I will wash it for you
# 桂皮 大料
Cinnamon, star anise
# 这个还真不是桂皮 这是肉桂
Actually this is not cinnamon, but Chinese cassia (chinese cinnamon)
# 咱家里使桂皮就行 辣椒
Cinnamon is also okay for cooking at home, dried chili pepper
# 这个蒜拍一下 出味
Crush the garlic to make its taste out
# 它的黏液的全给拍出来了
All its mucus has been crushed out
# 料很大 下味足
Bigger chunk makes taste more sufficient
# 这是您教我的我都记着呢
This was taught by you, and I still remember it
# 葱段姜片大蒜
Spring onion segments, ginger slices, and garlic chunks
# 泡这差不多了
The soaking time is enough
# 咱们到关键的一步 大家看好
Here comes the most critical step, pay attention please
# 有味使其出 无味使其入
Clear food’s original flavor if it has; add new flavor if it doesn’t
# 这就是烹饪原理
This is the basic principle of cooking
# 咱们得把咸菜的水给挤出去
We have to get rid of the water from the salted turnips
# 我跟您说为什么挤这水
Let me tell you the reason
# 如果不挤这水
If we don’t do this
# 就是咱们平时的炒咸菜疙瘩
Then the dish would become an ordinary fried salted turnip
# 外边的味儿进不去 里边的味儿出不来
Because the outer taste can’t go inside, and the inner taste can’t go outside
# 它吸外来的味更加饱满充分
It will absorb more taste from outside
# 你给我照我给你挤得了
You take photos for me, and let me help you squeeze it
# 换师父来 你得照师父
Now it’s my master’s turn; remember to take photos for your master
# 师父就是师父 老厉害了
Master is really master, very awesome
# 行了可以了 别一夸您就使劲大了
That’s enough, don’t work so hard because of the applause
# 挤完以后咸菜就变成这样了
Look how the salted turnip juliennes become after squeezing
# 成了干咸菜丝了
They have been dried
# 这个嚼起来比较有韧性了 有嚼头了
This makes it  tougher and more enjoyable to chew
# 这么多你看没了 看着多做出来就少了
So few now, they seem to be much less than before
# 咸味儿也没了 筋道了
And also there’s no saline taste now, they are more crunchy
# 师父师伯咱们开始炒咸菜
Master and master uncle, let’s begin cooking
# 这得多搁油 因为它吸油
Add more oil than usual, as the ingredient absorbs oil
# 咱把蒜子 姜下去
Add garlic and ginger
# 葱姜蒜炒香了
Cook until you can smell the aroma
# 如果家里边您要是有葱油的话
If you have scallion oil at home
# 直接使葱油炒也行 葱油更好啊
You could use it as the oil; scallion oil is even better
# 大料桂皮干辣椒
star anise, cinnamon, and dried chilli pepper
# 它出的是什么味 出的是肉香味
What does it smell like? The aroma of meat
# 咱们在家炒的时候一定给它炒透了
We have to cook it thoroughly when cooking at home
# 再补点油 这一炸料的油 它吃
Now we add a little more oil, it has absorbed a lot of oil
# 所以这油还要补一点
So we have to add a little more
# 这香味出来了
The aroma has come out
# 你看这辣椒还不能是糊
Don't overcook the chilli peppers
# 糊辣味就不对了
It’s wrong to have burnt taste
# 它得慢慢的沁炸
We need to fry them slowly
# 让它香味逐步的释放出来
To let its taste get out gradually
# 料香味 葱香味 姜香味
The mixed aroma of star anises, spring onions and gingers
# 各种的味道全部出来 现在正合适的时候
All kinds of taste have come out, so now it’s the perfect time
# 咸菜丝下锅 下锅了
Add salted turnip juliennes
# 炒的多干松啊 整个油都包裹在上面
So dry and soft, that they are all wrapped by oil
# 现在拌匀了以后关小点火
Mix they thoroughly and then turn down the heat
# 记住这个是不搁盐的
Remember no salt
# 千万别搁盐 搁盐就咸了
Never add salt, otherwise it will be too salty
# 咱们首先是 搁酱油就行了
Firstly add some soy sauce
# 一百七十克
170g
# 然后冰糖老抽是必须的
Then necessarily some white rock sugar and dark soy sauce
# 这颜色必须得够
The color must be enough
# 得一百克左右 出来这个颜色红亮红亮的
About 100g, to make the color red and bright finally
# 黄酒来一点
A little huangjiu rice wine
# 再加点酱油
A little soy sauce
# 刚才是生抽老抽  这回是酱油
Note that we have added light and dark soy sauces, but this time it’s soy sauce
# 然后白糖再来八十克
80g soft sugar
# 别瞧这么多糖 但是它吃不出糖味儿来
Even though the quality looks large, actually it doesn’t taste sugary at all
# 为什么使这冰糖老抽
Why add white rock sugar and dark soy sauce?
# 因为它出来以后成菜颜色好看 它红亮
Because it makes the dish look better, red and bright
# 这烹饪的绝学在哪儿 你看
So where is the secret of cooking, take a look
# 挤干净了 缩了没味儿了
(Turnips has been) squeezed, shrinked and now tasteless
# 让它慢慢的把这汤汁里的味再吸进去
To make the ingredient absorb taste from the soup slowly
# 一会儿咱们有一步也很关键
There’s another important step later
# 还要放锅上蒸 盛出来
We will steam the dish; take it out
# 咱们拿保温膜把它给包上
Wrap the dish with a piece of cling wrap
# 咱们这保鲜膜是可以高温的
This cling wrap is heat resisting
# 为了让水蒸气免得流进去
It’s to isolate the vapor out
# 咱们这开锅得蒸半个小时
We need to steam for half an hour
# 这会咱把这芝麻炒了
We could cook some sesames in the meanwhile
# 锅里什么都不用搁
Add nothing in the pot
# 就直接把芝麻倒进去 小火慢慢炒
Just pour the sesames in, and cook them slowly
# 最好买生的
Better to use unripe sesames
# 因为生芝麻炒出来以后现焙 特别香
Because unripe sesames has strong aroma after baking
# 好嘞关火
Okay, let’s turn off the heat
# 一定得炒出香味来 这个芝麻油够大的
We must cook enough time until the aroma comes out; so much sesame oil
# 这咸菜蒸了将近三十分钟
We have steamed about 30 mimutes
# 香么 香 太香了
Does it smell good? Yes, very good!
# 您看看放完冰糖老抽 这颜色多漂亮
The color is so wonderful after adding the white rock sugar and dark soy sauce
# 这个料头挑挑
Pick the condiments out
# 搁在一边给它晾凉了 装一罐里边封着
After cooling down, if we store the dish in a container
# 吃个一礼拜都没事儿  半个月都没事儿
We could eat it for one week, or even half a month
# 然后香菜 切中间连梗带叶的地儿
Then some cilantro, only keep the middle part with stem and some leaves
# 这咸菜凉了 芝麻多放点
Now it’s already cool, we could add more sesames
# 芝麻也是吃的时候再拌
Mix sesames just before eating
# 然后香菜也是吃的时候 现吃现拌
The same for cilantro, mix just before eating
# 这太香了大爷
This smells really good, Da Ye
# 油亮儿 为什么开始的时候
The oil looks bright, that is why initially
# 咱们的油得下够了
We had to add enough oil
# 这是空心的
The Huo Shao is hollow
# 我师父说了先给大爷
My master said, let Da Ye eat first
# 谢谢 谢谢 我先来一口
Thanks, I will taste first
# 我的天 你看大爷吃的香
My god, look how satisfied Da Ye is
# 这咔嚓你看 这一大口
Look, such a big bite
# 我再给我师父来一个
One more for my master
# 清晨早晨起来 熬一锅棒子碴粥
After getting up in the morning, boil a pot of corn congee
# 把咸菜往火烧里一夹
And put some salted vegetables into a Huo Shao
# 这就是生活
This is the life
# shift forward 00:06:06,500
# 上回您做了一个软炸鱼条
Last time you soft fried some fish pastes
# 他想问这个小苏打可不可以不加
People want to ask whether it’s possible not to add baking soda
# 没有小苏打可以用泡打粉代替吗
Can we use baking powder instead in case of a lack of baking soda?
# 可以
Sure
# 有些地方没有小苏打
If there’s no baking soda in your place
# 用泡打粉也可以
You can use baking powder instead
# 泡打粉是属于一个膨胀的作用
Baking powder is for inflation
# 小苏打是起外酥 坚挺
Baking soda is to make food crispy
# 你看我兑这个软炸糊的时候
You see when I made the paste for soft fry
# 我又加了点淀粉
I also added some starch
# 在这方面有很多网友也有一些质疑
Many people might argue
# 说软炸糊不加淀粉
That we shouldn’t add starch for soft fry paste
# 不是这样的
It’s not true
# 因为我们在烹调当中根据不同的原料
Because in cooking, according to different ingredients
# （原料）不同含的水分
With different moisture
# 我们在调糊当中要采取不同的方法来对应
We need to use different approaches when making batter
# 这样出来的效果才能达到饱满
To make the final result plump
# 加面粉也好 加淀粉也好
No matter flour or starch
# 您不信您可以试一试
You could simply have a try if that’s not convincing to you
# 这些东西绝对不是一成不变的 是绝对的东西
The cooking technical is not an absolute thing
# 你就是玉米淀粉
For example, if you even use corn starch
# 你就不加面粉完全使玉米淀粉
Without any flour
# 你加上合适的鸡蛋
But with proper quantity of eggs
# 你再加上油封起来
And then wrap with some oil
# 这个软炸糊一定很酥 也很脆
The soft fried batter will still be crispy
# 也很好吃
And also delicious
# 就这三样东西就能解决了
We can make it just with the three things above
# 只是这个配比关系要合适
As long as the proportion is right
# 一点问题没有
No Problem
# 要灵活
Cooking is flexible
# 不加面粉都行
It’s also okay without flour
# 要灵活运用
We must cook flexibly